Guide to the Lydia Winston Malbin Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Graphics, 1944-1988; Series III; (9.5 boxes)
  - Miro, Joan
    - "Barcelona Series, Lithograph IV" 4/5, 1944 (#G-32), 1972 (Box 31, Folder 376)
    - (Etching, hand-colored: 32/100) same pattern as #G-168 (#G-167) (Box 31, Folder 377)
    - (Etching, hand-colored: 4/30) same pattern as G-167 (#G-168) (Box 31, Folder 378)
  - Morris, Robert
    - "Earth Projects" (litho: 3/10) (#G-605) (Box 31, Folder 379)
  - Moser, Wilfred
    - Miscellaneous (Box 31, Folder 380)
  - Motherwell, Robert
    - Miscellaneous (Box 31, Folder 381)
  - Nesbitt, Lowell
    - Miscellaneous (Box 31, Folder 382)
  - Nevelson, Louise
    - "The Great Wall" (intaglio: 97/150), 1970 (#G-644), 1971 (Box 31, Folder 383)
  - Newman, Barnett
    - "The Moment" (silkscreen on plexiglass: 10/25), 1966 (#G-375), 1968 (Box 31, Folder 384)
  - Oldenberg, Claes
    - "Soft Scissors" (litho: 43/144), 1968 (#G-548) (Box 31, Folder 385)
  - Olitsky, Jules
    - Miscellaneous (Box 31, Folder 386)
  - Pechstein, Max
    - Miscellaneous (Box 31, Folder 387)
  - Pederson, Carl-Henning
    - Miscellaneous (Box 31, Folder 388)
  - Pfriem, Bernard
    - (#G-702): miscellaneous (Box 31, Folder 389)
  - Picasso, Pablo
    - Graphics: miscellaneous (Box 31, Folder 390)
    - Affiche: Valauris Exposition Peinture (lithograph color), 1956 (Box 31, Folder 391)
    - Affiches de Pablo Picasso: miscellaneous (Box 31, Folder 392)
    - "Don Quixote" (litho), 1955 (#G-391) (Box 31, Folder 393)
    - "Portraits Imaginaires" (lithograph color)' 1971 (#G-733, G-743) (Box 31, Folder 394)
  - Poliakoff, Serge
    - "Composition" (etching color), 1958 (#G-327), 1963 (Box 31, Folder 395)
  - Rauschenberg, Robert
    - Lists, etc. (Box 31, Folder 396)
    - "Accident" (litho: 25/29) 1963 (#G-371), 1965 (Box 31, Folder 397)
    - "Front Roll" (litho: 6/39), 1964 (#G-372) (Box 31, Folder 398)
    - "Poster", Jewish Museum (litho: 24/200) (#G-735), 1963
      See "Stunt Man"
    - "Stunt Man I" (Litho) (#G-355), 1964 (Box 31, Folder 399)
    - "Stunt Man II" (Litho) (#G-356), 1964 (Box 31, Folder 400)
  - Ray, Man
    - Untitled (etching, color: 49/150) (#G-578), 1969 (Box 32, Folder 401)
  - Reinhardt, Ad
    - "Ten Screenprints" (serigraphs: portfolio) (#G-273), 1969 (Box 32, Folder 402)
  - Richier, Germaine
    - "Praying Mantis" (etching: [76/100?]), (#G-414), circa 1947 (Box 32, Folder 403)
  - Riley, Bridget
    - "Fragment" (silkscreen on plexiglass: 2/10), 1965 (#G-576); Misc, 1969 (Box 32, Folder 404)
  - Rivers, Bridget
    - "Ford Chassis I", 1961 (#G-343), 1964 (Box 32, Folder 405)
  - Robinson, Sally Winston
    - General (Box 32, Folder 406)
    - "Abstraction" (cliche-verre) (#G-395), 1973
      See "Air Flares Afternoon"
    - "Air Flares Afternoon" (cliche-verre), 1974 (#G-773) (Box 32, Folder 407)
    - "Air Flares Evening" (cliche-verre), 1974 (#G-772) (Box 32, Folder 408)
    - "Air Flares Morning" (cliche-verre), 1974 (#G-774) (Box 32, Folder 409)
    - "Cliffs" (cliche-verre), 1973 (#G-741)
      See "Light and Shadow"
    - "Light and Shadow" (cliche-verre), 1976 (#G-795) (Box 32, Folder 410)
    - "Quietly, Wispering, They Touched" (cliche-verre), 1977 (Box 32, Folder 411)
    - "Veils in Sunlight" (cliche-verre), 1974 (Box 32, Folder 412)
    - "Window Dream" (cliche-verre), 1973 (Box 32, Folder 413)
  - Robinson, Suzanne
    - Miscellaneous (Box 32, Folder 414)
  - Rothschild, Judith
    - Miscellaneous (Box 32, Folder 415)
  - Rouault, Georges
    - "Busts of Two Women" (aquatint), 1928 (#G-68)
      See "Clown Tristis"
    - "Clown Tristis" (aquatint, color), [1934?] (#G-76), 1944 (Box 32, Folder 416)
  - Ruffins
    - "Harlem on my Mind" (litho), 1968 (#G-587) - Invoice only, 1969 (Box 32, Folder 417)
  - Russolo, Luigi
    - "Portrait of Nietzsche" (etching), c.1910 (#G-274), 1954 (Box 32, Folder 418)
  - Sandberg, William
    - Miscellaneous (Box 32, Folder 419)
  - Santomaso, Giuseppe
    - Brochure only (#G-284, G-344, G-410, G-448) (Box 32, Folder 420)
  - Scanovino, Emilio
    - "Relique" (painting, oil), 1959 -Gift to Harry Winston, Jr., 1960 (Box 32, Folder 421)
  - Seuphor, Michel
    - "August" (serigraph), 1964 (#G-737), 1972 (Box 32, Folder 422)
    - "La Danse au Velours" (drawing, ink on paper), 1958 (#G-187) (Box 32, Folder 423)
    - "Jeu dans l'ete" (serigraph: 69/100), 1971 (#G-736), 1972 (Box 32, Folder 424)
    - Album of 10 (serigraphs), 1961 (#G-203) (Box 33, Folder 425)
  - Shahn, Ben
    - Affiche (poster) (litho, colored) (Box 33, Folder 426)
  - Smith, Kimber
    - Illustration from "Bye Bye Love" (lithograph color) (#G-367): miscellaneous (Box 33, Folder 427)
  - Smith, Richard
    - "Edward Gordon Craig Series II" (lithograph color), 1968 (#G-56), 1970 (Box 33, Folder 428)
  - Sottsass, Ettore
    - Miscellaneous (Box 33, Folder 429)
  - Stasik, Andrew
    - Miscellaneous (Box 33, Folder 430)
  - Stella, Frank
    - Poster for Documenta IV (litho, color), 1968 (#G-547) (Box 33, Folder 431)
    - One of Portfolio of 10 works by 10 painters ("1st print"), 1964 (Box 33, Folder 432)
  - Sugai, Kim
    - "Samurai" (#G-30) (Box 33, Folder 433)
  - Taeuber-Arp, Sophie
    - Miscellaneous (Box 33, Folder 434)
  - Tal Coat, Pierre
    - Affiche (lithograph) (#G-582), 1969 (Box 33, Folder 435)
  - Tanguy, Yves
    - "Shadow Country" (Box 33, Folder 436)
  - Tinguely, Jean
    - Untitled (litho: 117/300) (#G-739) (Box 33, Folder 437)
  - Toulouse-Lautrec, Henri
    - "Marcel Lender Doing the Bolero..." (lithograph) (#G-60), 1971 (Box 33, Folder 438)
  - Tzara, Tristan
    - Miscellaneous (Box 33, Folder 439)
  - Vasarely, Vistor de
    - Miscellaneous (Box 33, Folder 440)
    - Poster (serigraph) (#G-741), Bill for framing only (Box 33, Folder 441)
  - Villon, Jacques
    - Miscellaneous (Box 33, Folder 442)
  - Warhol, Andy
    - Poster (serigraph), 1970, Bill for framing (#G-742), 1971 (Box 33, Folder 443)
  - Wayne, June
    - "Illustration for 'Songs and Sonnets' by John Donne. 'Goe Catche a..." (Box 33, Folder 444)
  - Weiss, Edward H.
    - Miscellaneous (Box 34, Folder 445)
  - Wengenroth, Richard
    - "Greeting" (#G-514), 1967 (Box 34, Folder 446)
  - Wesselman, Tom
    - "Look At" (affiche: lithograph color) (#G-586) [1969?] (Box 34, Folder 447)
  - Wilson, Wes
    - Miscellaneous (Box 34, Folder 448)
  - Photographs
    - Clerque, Lucien
      - Miscellaneous (Box 34, Folder 449)
    - Domela, Cesar
      - Miscellaneous (Box 34, Folder 450)
    - Jones, E. Powis
      - "There are No Cats or Dogs in Chinatown" (colored xerox), 1986 (Box 34, Folder 451)
    - Linn, Judy
      - "Maple Twig, Thai Silk" (photograph), 1987 (PH-54), 1988 (Box 34, Folder 452)
    - Lissitsky, El
      - "Self-Portrait" (photograph), c. 1923-24 (PH-53), 1949 (Box 34, Folder 453)
    - Ruben, Ernestine
      - Miscellaneous (Box 34, Folder 454)
  - Greetings
    - Winston, Barbara
      - Photographs (Box 34, Folder 455)
      - University of Michigan Museum of Art exhibit 1963-64 (Box 34, Folder 456)
      - Greetings Lists, 1966 (Box 34, Folder 457)
      - Stamford (CT) Art and Nature Center exhibit, 1981 (Box 34, Folder 458)
    - Arp, Jean
      - Greeting Card from the Artist (Box 34, Folder 459)
    - Longo, Vincent
      - Miscellaneous (Box 34, Folder 460)
    - Morandi, Giorgio
      - Gravure de Morandi (Box 34, Folder 461)
- Drawings, 1946-1985; Series IV; (5.25 boxes)
  This series consists of documentation for drawings in Malbin's art collection. For each work, files include: documentation concerning how the art work was obtained, research, negotiations, arrangement for shipment, and notes; photographs; conservation records; correspondence with the artist and with the family, regarding the work and requests to sell; exhibition records; publication record; use by scholars; gallery materials, including brochures and catalogs; other works by the artist; and secondary materials, regarding the work, regarding the artist, and/or regarding the particular art movement.
  - Alechinsky, Pierre
    - "Personages", 1927 (#G-243) (Box 35, Folder 462)
  - Archipenko, Alexander
    - "Nude" No.1, ca. 1912-15, 1915 (Box 35, Folder 463)
    - "Nude" No.2, ca. 1912-13, 1915 (Box 35, Folder 464)
  - Arp, Jean
    - "Abstract Form", 1922, (#G-181), 1954 (Box 35, Folder 465)
    - "Abstract Form", 1922 (#G-182), 1954 (Box 35, Folder 466)
    - "Portrait of Tristan Tzara", 1920 (#G-191) (Box 35, Folder 467)
    - Drawing for Sculpture, "Torso de Geant" (no work) (Box 35, Folder 468)
  - Balla, Giacomo
    - "Autoritratto" or "Portrait of Balla", 1920 (#G-178) (Box 35, Folder 469)
    - "Landscape" (#G-188) (Box 35, Folder 470)
    - "Vortice Linea di Velocita" (#G-176) (Box 35, Folder 471)
  - Barlow, Myron
    - 12 drawings (references to, no work) (#G-777 - #G-788) (Box 35, Folder 472)
  - Boccioni, Umberto
    See Boccioni Drawings and Etchings
  - Brancusi, Constantin
    - "La Pyramide de Fatale" (#G-758) (Box 35, Folder 473)
  - Calder, Alexander
    - Photo of LWM with sketches for mobile, 5 Jan 1949 (#G-144) (Box 35, Folder 474)
  - Copley, William
    - Study for painting, "Last Kiss", 1965 (#G-412) (Box 35, Folder 475)
  - Dorazio, Piero
    - Drawing (ink & wash) (#G-186) (Box 35, Folder 476)
  - Ernst, Max
    - "Come Into the Continents", 1926 (Box 35, Folder 477)
  - Fisher, Lindsey
    - "Black in a Bright Light" (#G-917), 1985 (Box 35, Folder 478)
  - Gris, Juan
    - "Man with a Guitar", 1918 (#G-175), 1950 (Box 35, Folder 479)
  - Klee, Paul
    - "Munich", 1910 (#G-205), 1957 (Box 35, Folder 480)
  - Le Fresnaye, Roger
    - "Composition with a Trumpet" (#G-163) (Box 35, Folder 481)
  - Leger, Ferdnand
    - "Still Life", 1921 (#G-162), 1952 (Box 36, Folder 482)
  - Levinson, Mon
    - "Untitled" (#G-759), 1972 (Box 36, Folder 483)
  - Masson, Andre
    - "Nude under a Fig Tree", 1944 (#G-165), 1946 (Box 36, Folder 484)
  - Matisse, Henri
    - "The Velvet Gown", 1936 (#G-174), 1948 (Box 36, Folder 485)
    - Secondary material (Box 36, Folder 486)
  - Moore, Tony
    - ______ (#256) (Box 36, Folder 487)
  - Phillips, David
    - "Boundaries and Limitations" (Box 36, Folder 488-489)
  - Picabia, Francis
    - "Reveil Matin", 1919 (#G-171), 1954 (Box 36, Folder 490)
  - Picasso, Pablo
    - "Portrait of a Woman Seated under a Light", 1938 (#G-189), 1948 (Box 36, Folder 491)
    - "Still Life", 1913 (#G-157), 1947 (Box 36, Folder 492)
  - Seuphor, Michel
    - Drawing (ink on yellow paper) (#G-187) (Box 37, Folder 493)
  - Severini, Gino
    - Greeting Card, 1958 (#G-91), conservation report only; Greeting, 1963 (#G-302) (1970), framing bill only (Box 37, Folder 494)
    - "Abstraction", 1952 (#G-1) (Box 37, Folder 495)
    - "Study for the Armored Train", 1914 (#G-164) (Box 37, Folder 496)
    - "Study for Dancer Beside the Sea", 1913 (#G-206), 1952 (Box 37, Folder 497)
  - Tzara, Tristan (et al)
    - Fragment of tablecloth (#G-143) (Box 37, Folder 498)
  - Wesselman, Tom
    - "Study for a Still Life", 1963 (#G-376), 1964 (Box 37, Folder 499)
  - Xceron, Jean
    - "Composition #6" (drawing on paper), 1933 (#269), 1979 (Box 37, Folder 500)
  - Boccioni Drawings & Etchings: Joshua C. Taylor. The Graphic Work of Umberto Boccioni. The Museum of Modern Art, New York. Distributed by Doubleday & Co., 1961. (Heavily annotated by LWM)
    - Early Documents, 1956-1958, 1964 (Box 37, Folder 501-502)
    - Lists (Box 37, Folder 503-506)
    - Correspondence (Box 38, Folder 507)
    - Correspondence: Art Institute of Chicago, 1956-1971 (Box 38, Folder 508)
    - Correspondence: Museum of Modern Art, 1960-1962 (Box 38, Folder 509-510)
    - Correspondence: Harold W. Tribolet, 1957-1959 (Box 38, Folder 511)
    - Values: Photographs; Medium; Malbin Numbers (Box 38, Folder 512)
    - pencil X-1 "Corner Building with Chimneys", 1910; pencil X-1A "Landscape Seen through a Row of Six Tree Trunks (Trellis)", c. 1907; pencil X-2 "Head of a Bull" (1907-8); pencil X-3 "Back of a Workman", c. 1909-10; pencil X-4 "Study of a Bull's Body" 1907-08; pencil X-5 "Study of a Bull's Forelegs", 1907-08 (Box 38, Folder 513)
    - pencil X-6 "Curly-Haired Child (Fiammetta)", 1910; pencil X-7 "Study of a Bull Head and Leg", 1907-08 (Box 38, Folder 514)
    - ink X-8 "Mob Gathered Around a Monument", 1908 (Box 38, Folder 515)
    - pencil X-9 "Two Walking Women in Street Dress", c. 1910; X-11 "Analytical Study of Head of Woman Against Buildings", c.1911-12 (Box 38, Folder 516)
    - etching X-12 "Boccioni's Mother Crocheting", 1907 (Box 38, Folder 517)
    - pencil X-13 "Analytical Study of the Shoulder and Breast of a Woman", 1912; pencil X-14 "Head of a Horse with Blinkers" (in upper left 'Corbeau'), c.1909-10 (Box 38, Folder 518)
    - X-15 "Woman Leaning on a Chair" or "Boccioni's Sister", c.1909 (Box 38, Folder 519)
    - pencil X-16 "Two Standing Women in Street Dress", c.1910; pencil X-17 "Curly Haired Child (Fiametta)", 1910; X-18 NOTHING (Box 38, Folder 520)
    - charcoal X-19 "Analytical Study of a Woman's Profile", 1911; X-20 "Embracing a Couple on a Cloud over a Lake with Floating Heads", 1908; X-21 NOTHING; etching X-22 "Boccioni's Mother Sewing", c.1910 (Box 38, Folder 521)
    - X-23 "Study for the Painting, 'The Riot'", 1911; pencil X-24 "Arbor with Trees in the Background", c.1908-10 wash on (Box 38, Folder 522)
    - paper X-25 "Head of Boccioni's Mother", c.1914 (Box 38, Folder 523)
    - X-26 "Standing Woman with Folded Arms", n.d.; X-27 "Analytical Study of a Woman's Head Against the Light with Window Frame", 1912; X-28 "Sheet of Studies with Three Landscapes and Two Allegorical Figures", c.1908; X-29 NOTHING (Box 38, Folder 524)
    - pencil X-30 "Seated Woman; Study for the Story of a Seamstress", 1908; pencil X-31 "Plant", c.1910; pencil X-32 "Head of a Horse with Feedbag",c.1909-10; X-33 "Study for Painting, 'Modern Idol'", 1911 (Box 38, Folder 525)
    - X-34 "Study for 'The City Rises'", 1910;pencil X-35 "Study of two hands and forearms", c.1907;X-35 NOTHING;X-36 NOTHING;pencil X-38 "Figure of an Old Woman", c.1909 (Box 38, Folder 526)
    - pencil X-39 "Standing Workman with a Cap", c.1909;pencil X-40 "Sheet of Studies including two compositions for 'The City Rises' and two scenes for "City Crowd'", 1910;X-40A "Study for 'The City Rises'", 1910;pencil X-41 "Bust of a Woman with a Black Hat", c.1910 (Box 38, Folder 527)
    - X-42 "Study for painting, 'The City Rises'";pencil X-43 "Harnessed Horse", 1910;X-44 "Harnessed Horse with Feedbag", c.1909-10;X-45 "Harnessed Horse with Collar", 1909-10 (Box 38, Folder 528)
    - pencil X-46 "Head of a Bull", 1907-08;X-47 NOTHING;pencil X-48 "Bust of Boccioni's Mother", 1912;pencil X-49 "Workman Wearing a Derby, Inverted Head of Man with Cap Lower Right", 1910 (Box 38, Folder 529)
    - X-50 NOTHING;X-51 NOTHING;X-52 NOTHING;etching X-52 "Head of a Boy", 1910 (Box 38, Folder 530)
    - X-54 "Study for 'Lutto' or 'Morning'", 1910 (Box 38, Folder 531)
    - X-55 "Maria Sacchi Reading", 1907;X-56 NOTHING;X-57 NOTHING;X-58 "Study for the sculpture "Head plus Light plus Window" (Box 38, Folder 532)
    - etching X-59 "Male Cadaver" [or] "The Drowned Man", 1909-10;X-60 "The Bridge of Ganboloita", 1910;pencil X-61 "Bald Headed Man with Moustache", 1910 (Box 38, Folder 533)
    - pencil X-62 "Curly Haired Child", 1910;pencil X-63 "Study of an Arm with Hand Resting on the Shoulder", 1907;X-64 NOTHING;pencil X-65 "Back of a Fashionably Dressed Woman", 1909;pencil X-66 "Back of a Workman in Full Trousers", 1909-10;X-67 NOTHING (Box 38, Folder 534)
    - X-68 "Head Against Light", n.d.;pen & ink X-69 "Sheet of Studies of Window and Foliage and Study of Arm", c.1908;crayon X-70 "Street with Houses", 1911;X-71 "Boccioni's Sister";X-72 "Study for Allegory of the Nativity", 1908;X-73C "Study of the City with Overpass" (Box 38, Folder 535)
    - X-73A;X-73B;X-73D;pencil X-73E "Woman Resting Her Chin on Her Hand", 1907;X-74 NOTHING;X-75 NOTHING;X-76 NOTHING (Box 38, Folder 536)
    - X-77 NOTHING;X-78 "Study for painting 'Milanese Countryside'", c.1907;X-79 NOTHING;X-80 NOTHING;X-81 NOTHING;X-82 NOTHING (Box 38, Folder 537)
    - pencil X-83 "Male Figure in Motion", 1913;pen & ink X-84 "Composition Sketch for 'Mourning'", 1910;X-85 "Crowd in Front of Corner Building", 1910 (Box 39, Folder 538)
    - X-86 NOTHING; X-87 "Studies for painting 'The Dream: Paolo and Francesca'"; X-88 "Sheet of Studies with two portraits of a man, related to the drawings for a book - plate, 'In Letizia Ben Fare'"; X-89 "Head of a woman, possibly related to studies for bookplate, 'In Letizia Ben Bare'" (Box 39, Folder 539)
    - X-90 NOTHING; X-91 "Study for 'The Laugh'", 1910-11 (Box 39, Folder 540)
    - X-92 NOTHING;pencil X-93 "Workman from the Rear", c.1909-10 [empty];X-94 NOTHING;X-95 NOTHING;X-96 NOTHING;X-97 "Three Horses Tended by Men", study for "The City Rises", c.1909-1910;X-98 "Sheet of Studies for 'Mourning' with head of old woman and cursory study of head and hands";X-99-X-121 NOTHING (Box 39, Folder 541)
    - X-122 "Self-Portrait", 1910 (Box 39, Folder 542)
    - charcoal over grey wash X-123 "Young Woman Reading (Inez)", 1910 (Box 39, Folder 543)
    - X-124 NOTHING;X-125 "Seated Woman Leaning on Her Elbow (Inez)", 1909-10;X-126 NOTHING;pencil X-127 "Study of a Woman in a Loose Robe", c.1909 (Box 39, Folder 544)
    - chalk & watercolor X-128 "Portrait of Boccioni's Mother", 1915-16 (Box 39, Folder 545)
    - pencil X-129 "Tryptich - Homage to Mother" (Box 39, Folder 546)
    - pencil X-130 "Standing Nude Girl", 1907 (Box 39, Folder 547)
    - X-131 "Portrait of Silvia", 1915 (Box 39, Folder 548)
    - pencil X-132 "States of Mind III: The Farewells", 1911 (Box 39, Folder 549)
    - ink X-132A "States of Mind II: Those Who Go", 1912 (Box 39, Folder 550)
    - X-133 NOTHING; X-134 "Boccioni's Mother at a Table"; X-135 "Planar Study of a Woman's Head (Ines?)"; X-136 "Sheet of Studies with Male Nude from the Back" (Box 39, Folder 551)
    - pencil X-137 "Study of a Man's Forearm", c.1907;X-138 NOTHING;pencil X-139 "Reclining Male Nude" (Box 39, Folder 552)
    - pencil X-140 "Study of Hands";X-141 NOTHING;gouache X-142 "Young Man on the Bank of a River";X-143 NOTHING;X-144 NOTHING;X-145 NOTHING;X-146 NOTHING;X-147 NOTHING;X-148 NOTHING;X-149 "Seated Male Nude", 1909-10;X-150 to X-161 NOTHING;X-162 "Pianist and Listener", c. 1907 [empty] (Box 39, Folder 553)
    - pen & ink X-163 "Man with Newspaper in Café", c. 1912;X-164 to X-168 NOTHING;X-169 "Head of a Woman -- Boccioni's Sister", 1909-10;X-170 "Boccioni's Sister Leaning on Her Hand", 1911;pencil X-171 "Young Woman Sewing", 1909-10 (Box 39, Folder 554)
    - ink X-172 "Boccioni's Mother in Bed", 1908;X-173 NOTHING;X-174 "Man at a Café Table, Paris", c.1913;X-175 to X-183 NOTHING;X-184 "Standing Figure of a Woman" verso of "The Mother Sewing" [empty];X-185 to X-196 NOTHING;X-197 "Sewing Machine (Study for 'The Seamstress')", 1908 (Box 39, Folder 555)
    - X-198 to X-202 NOTHING;pencil X-203 "Study for Berita Solitudo"; X-204 to X-208 NOTHING; X-209 "Portrait of a Young Man"; X-210 "Young Woman Reading" (Box 39, Folder 556)
    - X-211 "Mother Feeding Child" or "Mother and Child at the Table"; X-212 "Seated Woman Reading", 1909-10;chalk X-213 "Wheelbarrow"; X-214 to X-320 NOTHING; X-320A "Man Laying Paving Stones", Study for "The Street Pavers"; X-320B to X-320C NOTHING; X-320D "Two Workmen", Study for "The Street Pavers" (Box 39, Folder 557)
    - Versos (Box 39, Folder 558)
    - Additional prints: miscellaneous (Box 39, Folder 559-560)
    - Small albums: orange (Box 39, Folder 561)
    - Small albums: Red & green (Box 39, Folder 562)
  - Exhibitions
    - Catalogs (Box 40, Folder 563)
    - Correspondence (Box 40, Folder 564)
    - Secondary materials (Box 40, Folder 565)
    - Photographs of Boccioni, his family and friends
      See Series VII: Personal Photographs
- Objects of Art, 1940-1972; Series V; (1.25 boxes)
  This series consists of documentation for objects in Malbin's art collection. For each work, files include: documentation concerning how the art work was obtained, research, negotiations, arrangement for shipment, and notes; photographs; conservation records; correspondence with the artist and with the family, regarding the work and requests to sell; exhibition records; publication record; use by scholars; gallery materials, including brochures and catalogs; other works by the artist; and secondary materials, regarding the work, regarding the artist, and/or regarding the particular art movement.
  - General
    - OBJECTS OF ART: ASSORTED (Box 40, Folder 566)
    - OBJECTS OF ART: VALUES 1963 & PHOTOS (GROUP) (Box 40, Folder 567)
    - AFRICAN;Beaker (#169), mask (#170), sensitive mask (#171) (Box 40, Folder 568)
    - ART DECO;(silver) (Box 40, Folder 569)
    - CAKE PLATE, AMERICAN (glass) (Box 40, Folder 570)
    - CANDELABRA;(Silver) By James Woolsey, Gift to Albert Kahn from George Book and James Scribb, 1917 (Box 40, Folder 571)
    - CHEST, AMERICAN;(Curly maple & cherry, 18th century) (#173) (Box 40, Folder 572)
    - FURNISHINGS: WINSTON - MALBIN HOMES (Box 40, Folder 573)
    - PRE-COLUMBIAN ART: 11 pieces (#172) (Box 40, Folder 574)
    - SPANISH ROMANESQUE CAPITALS;(Limestone) (#266, 267) Conservation report only (Box 40, Folder 575)
    - STAINED GLASS SET IN LEAD;Art Nouveau landscape, early 20th century (#247), 1972 (Box 40, Folder 576)
  - Balla Giacomo
    - Palette & brushes, c.1925 (#167), Note only (Box 40, Folder 577)
  - Boccioni, Umberto
    - Palette (168) (Box 40, Folder 578)
  - Brancusi, Constantin
    - "The Kiss" (painted egg shell) (#188) (Box 40, Folder 579)
  - Calder, Alexander
    - Rug (Box 40, Folder 580)
  - Devore, Richard
    - Ceramic plate, 1970 (#240) (Box 40, Folder 581)
  - Duchamp, Marcel
    - "Rotreliefs" (6 cardboard disks printed in litho.), 1953;Gift to the Detroit Institute of Arts, 1975 (Box 40, Folder 582)
  - Grotall, Maija
    - Ceramic bowl (#113), 1967 (Box 40, Folder 583)
    - Ceramic vase, 1952 (#166), 1940 (Box 40, Folder 584)
  - Morrell, Lee
    - Rug, 1970 (#121);(Design taken from Balla painting) (Box 41, Folder 585)
  - Picasso, Pablo
    - "Female Figure" (ceramic): note only, circa 1952 (Box 41, Folder 586)
    - "Owl" (ceramic), 1952 (#101) (Box 41, Folder 587)
    - "Plate with Bull's Head", note only, 1952 (Box 41, Folder 588)
    - Rug (#99), 1960 (Box 41, Folder 589)
    - Rug (#228), 1964 (Box 41, Folder 590)
  - Ramie, Suzanne (dealer for Picasso)
    - Ceramic Plates, note only (Box 41, Folder 591)
  - Stella, Frank
    - Medallion (invoice only), 1969 (Box 41, Folder 592)
  - Visser, Carel
    - Brochure only (Box 41, Folder 593)
- Correspondence, 1959-1989; Series VI; (5.5 boxes)
  This series consists of correspondence that was kept together as a group by Mrs. Malbin. Additional correspondence can be found throughout the papers.
  Part of the correspondence is arranged alphabetically by correspondent. The other part of the correspondence is arranged chronologically by year.
  - A (Box 41, Folder 594)
  - Ajo, Aldo, 1959 (Box 41, Folder 595)
  - Armitage, Kenneth (Box 41, Folder 596)
  - Arp, Jean and Marguerite (Box 41, Folder 597)
  - B (Box 41, Folder 598)
  - Barr, Alfred (Box 41, Folder 599)
  - C (Box 41, Folder 600)
  - Callery, Mary (Box 41, Folder 601)
  - Cooke, Howard L. (Box 41, Folder 602)
  - D (Box 41, Folder 603)
  - Degand, Léon (Box 42, Folder 604)
  - Denman, Bill (Box 42, Folder 605)
  - Detroit Institute of Arts, 1973-1974 (Box 42, Folder 606)
  - Dorazio, Piero and Virginia (Box 42, Folder 607)
  - Dorner, Alexander (Box 42, Folder 608)
  - E (Box 42, Folder 609)
  - F (Box 42, Folder 610)
  - Fried, Rose (Box 42, Folder 611)
  - G (Box 42, Folder 612)
  - Guggenheim, Peggy (Box 42, Folder 613)
  - Guilbert, Claire (Box 42, Folder 614)
  - Guilbert, Claire and Gilles (Box 42, Folder 615)